Voravee Ruengaramrut

E-mail: voravee.r@gmail.com Tel. 083-644-5696

Address: 698/306 Phaholyothin Samsennai Phayathai Bangkok 10400



Key Highlights

Service Innovation Process | Customer Engagement | Knowledge Management | Change Management | Gamification

- Researcher and Speaker of Service Innovation, Customer Engagement, Knowledge management and Gamification.
- Be Project Manager to implement co-design process to various national level project under one of non-profit organization.
- Be the Knowledge Manager to implement Knowledge Management to utilize agriculture knowledge across Thailand under one of non-Profit Organization
- Be Project Manager of Gallup Consulting to monitor and ensure quality of operation and consulting projects.

Research Interests

The Current research project has focused on the relationship between customer engagement and customer and organization co-design in service innovation process by using gamification as a moderating factor.

Published Paper

Ruengaramrut, V., Ribiere, Vincent., Ammi, Chantal. A Component Diagram Presenting a Gamified Environment Supporting Customer Engagement in a Service Innovation Process. 2015. Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intellectual Capital Knowledge management&Orgnisational Learning ICICKM.

Professional Development

2015 Gamification

Coursera Verified Certificates, License XBA7ECL6NT

2015 Designing Gamification Level 1

Udemy, License UC-6E13RJC0 (Received on May, 2015)

2016 Gamification - engage customers in your business
Udemy, License UC-AN8NC5LQ (Received on February, 2016)

Professional Experiences

Nov 2015 - Present: Be a volunteer since Aug 2015

Collaborate We Can Project - Project Manager, Konglakuentin Project - Knowledge manager

Scenario Thailand Foundation, Bangkok Thailand

(NGO foundation that uses Social Lab, the mechanism of finding practical solutions to serious issues in Thailand through transformative scenario planning and the collaborative between all different entities involved. The outcome is the massive change within the society.)

- Responsible for the success of the action plans across various teams.
- Design & Create survey to measure project effectiveness, participant & customer engagement and satisfaction level.
- Analyze participant engagement and satisfaction level toward program and workshop process.
- Regular cooperate with team on all project-related matters.
- Ensuring the effective preparation and delivery of all project events and meetings and production of all necessary documentation.
- Taking responsibility for the effective flow of information between team members, participants in project activities.
- Lead Knowledge Management for Konklakuentin project.
- Manage information, time, tasks/processes in knowledge management part.
- Cooperate and provide information for media team.
- Design system to encourage and generate knowledge sharing among participant and core team for Konklakuentin project.

Jan 2013 – Nov 2015:

Consulting & Market Research - Project Operation Manager

Gallup Organization, Bangkok Thailand

(One of the top consulting firms who specialized in Customer & Employee Engagement. Gallup provides both research and business intervention consulting services to clients)

- Managed project for 100% of Bangkok portfolio.
- Created a project plan which identifies and sequences the activities needed to successfully complete the project.
- Determined the resources (time, budget, equipment, people, etc.) required to complete the project both for Thailand team and international team.
- Defined scope of work for all projects.
- Developed a schedule for project completion that effectively allocates the resources to the activities.

- Established a communication schedule to update stakeholders including appropriate staff in the organization on the progress of the project.
- Reviewed the quality of the work completed with the project team on a regular basis to ensure that it meets the project standards.
- Monitored and approve all budgeted project expenditures.
- Ensured that the project deliverables are on time, within budget and at the required level of quality.

Key Achievements at Gallup Organization

 Successfully managed a diverse range of projects from conception through implementation and received "Rising Star" reward in 2014 and "Most Valuable Player" reward in 2013 and 2014

Apr 2012 – Dec 2012:

IT Help Desk Officer

United Nations ESCAP, Bangkok Thailand

(An intergovernmental organization to promote international co-operation)

- Provided technical and troubleshooting assistance related to computer hardware and software, mobile devices and other tech tools and products.
- Responded to requests for technical assistance in person, via phone, electronically.
- Tracked and routed problems and requests and document resolutions.
- Informed management of recurring problems.

Dec 2011 - Mar 2012:

Lecturer in Information and Technology Department

Thai-Nichi Institute Technology, Bangkok Thailand

(Thai-Japanese technology university in Thailand)

- Delivered lectures for database and e-commerce class.
- Designed, prepared and developed teaching materials.
- Assessed students' coursework.
- Set and marking examinations.
- Supported students through a pastoral or advisory role.
- Carried out administrative tasks related to the department.

Guest speaker at Huachiew Chalermprakiet University in 2014

- Knowledge Economy
- Knowledge management and ASEAN

Education

Bangkok University (In Progress) Bangkok, Thailand

Degree: PhD program in Knowledge and Innovation management

Research keyword: Customer engagement, Gamification, Service innovation and Service

innovation process

WasedaUniversity Graduate School of Information, Production and systems.

Kitakyushu campus, Japan (04/2009 –03/2011)

Degree: Mater of Engineering, Major in data engineering

RitsumeikanAsia Pacific University

Oita, Japan (04/2005 –03/2009) **Degree:** Bachelor of Social Science